Edna O'Brien papers, circa 1939-2000
Emory University
- Printed material, 1958-1999, Series 6; Boxes 84-91, OP4-16
  - Writings about O'Brien, Subseries 6.2; Box 85: folders 19-31 - Box 89; OP4-16
    - Reviews: Short Story Collections
    - The Love Object, 1968 (Box 85, Folder 19)
    - A Scandalous Woman, and Other Stories, 1974 (Box 85, Folder 20)
    - Mrs. Reinhardt, and Other Stories, 1980 (Box 85, Folder 21)
    - A Fanatic Heart: Selected Short Stories of Edna O'Brien, 1984 (Box 85, Folder 22)
    - Lantern Slides, 1990 (Box 85, Folder 23)
    - Reviews: Novels
    - The Country Girls, 1960 (Box 85, Folder 24)
    - Casualties of Peace, 1966 (Box 85, Folder 25)
    - A Pagan Place, 1970 (Box 85, Folder 26)
    - Johnny I Hardly Knew You, 1978 (Box 85, Folder 27)
    - The Country Girls Trilogy and Epilogue, 1989 (Box 85, Folder 28)
    - The High Road, 1988 [1 of 2] (Box 85, Folder 29)
    - The High Road, 1988 [2 of 2] (Box 85, Folder 30)
    - Time and Tide, 1992 [1 of 2] (Box 85, Folder 31)
    - Time and Tide, 1992 [2 of 2] (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - House of Splendid Isolation, 1994 [1 of 2] (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - House of Splendid Isolation, 1994 [2 of 2] (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Down By the River, 1996 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Wild Decembers, 1999 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Reviews: Drama
    - A Pagan Place, 1970 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - X,Y, and Zee, 1972 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - The Gathering, 1974 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Mrs. Reinhardt, from Her Own Story, 1981 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Virginia, 1981 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Reviews: Juvenile
    - The Dazzle, 1981 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Tales for the Telling, 1986 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Reviews: Nonfiction
    - Mother Ireland, 1976 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - James Joyce, 1999 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Profiles and Interviews
    - "The Alchemy of Edna O'Brien," by Caleb; Davies, in Telegraph Sunday Magazine, 8 July 1979 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - "The Apotheosis of Our St. Edna," by John Boland, in The Irish Times, 10 August 1996 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - "The Art of Fiction LXXXII," by Shusha Guppy, in The Paris Review, Summer 1984 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - "The Booker Prize Shortlist," in The Sunday Telegraph, 13 September 1992 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - "Books of Blood and Cochineal," by Peter Conrad, in The Sunday Review, 11 August 1996 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - "Booksellers Report on Christmas Business," in Publisher's Weekly, 21 December 1984 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - "Brave New Novels by Leading Irish Authors," by Mary Rose Doorly, in The Irish Herald, May 1997 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - "Bravo, Edna," by Helen Meany, in The Irish Times, 24 August 1996 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - "Casting a Cold Eye," by James F. Clarity, in The New York Times (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - "Catholic Childhood's Long Legacy of Fear," by Frances Welch (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - "Ceasefire and Censorship Dominant Themes at Adams Book Promotion," by Maol Muire Tynan, in The Irish Times, 16 September 1994 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - "Country Girl," by Seamus Hosey, in RTE Guide, 23 August 1996 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - "Country Girls Author Says She is No 'Scarlet Woman,'" by Tom McPhall, in The Examiner, 20 August 1996 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - "The Country Girl Goes Home," by Miriam Lord, in Irish Independent, 2 July 1991 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - "The Country Girl Revisited," by Susan O'Grady Fox, in Irish America, November 1986 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - " Country Girls Gets a Launch," by Edward Cunningham, in The Independent, 8 June 1988 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - "Country Matters," by Nicholas Wroe, in The Guardian, 2 October 1999 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - "Dame Edna," by Eileen Battersby, in The Irish Times, 12 September 1992 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - "Dame Edna," by Ciaran Carty, in The Tribune Magazine, 18 August 1996 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - "Doing the Real Thing," by Jan Moir, in The Guardian, 16 September 1992 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - "Double for Commitments," by Stephen O'Brien, in Irish Independent, 7 December 1991 (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - "Drama of a Literary Duet," by Eileen Battersby, in The Irish Times, 5 August 1996 (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - "Edna in the Pulpit," in The Irish Post, 4 March 1972 (Box 87, Folder 23)
    - "Edna O'Brien," by Patricia Boyle Haberstroh (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - "Edna O'Brien," by Molly McQuade, in Publisher's Weekly, 18 May 1992 (Box 87, Folder 25)
    - "Edna O'Brien: A Beautiful, Eccentric Novelist Looks at Her Life" (Box 87, Folder 26)
    - "Edna O'Brien, Escritora Que Nos Estaba Destinada: Poniatowska," by Monica Mateos, in La Jornada, 22 March 1998 (Box 87, Folder 27)
    - "Edna O'Brien in Her Single Bliss," by Mary Kenny, in London Evening Standard, 28 May 1976 (Box 87, Folder 28)
    - "Edna O'Brien: 'Look, I Have Come Through,'" by Deirdre Purcell, in The Sunday Tribune, 22 July 1984 (Box 87, Folder 29)
    - "Edna O'Brien: Miles from Melancholy," by Caroline Walsh, in The Irish Times, 11 June 1988 (Box 87, Folder 30)
    - "Edna O'Brien Talks to David Heycock About Her New Novel, A Pagan Place," by David Heycock, in The Listener, 7 May 1970 (Box 87, Folder 31)
    - "Edna O'Brien's Fanatic Heart," by Caroline Drewes (Box 87, Folder 32)
    - "Edna O'Brien's Hard Edge of Heartbreak," by David Streitfeld, in International Herald Tribune, 31 July 1992 (Box 87, Folder 33)
    - "Edna O'Brien's Haunting Origins, by Laura Evenson (Box 87, Folder 34)
    - "Edna O'Brien's Rituals," by Ann Agranoff, in The New York Times Magazine, 23 April 1989 (Box 87, Folder 35)
    - "Edna Still Looking for Man of Her Dreams," by Sue Corbett, in Sunday Life, 20 September 1992 (Box 87, Folder 36)
    - "Edna Weathers Rough Waters," by Una Brankin, in Sunday Press, 4 October 1992 (Box 87, Folder 37)
    - "Enchanting Edna!," by Barbara McKeon, in The Irish Press, 3 February 1993 (Box 87, Folder 38)
    - "Encountering Edna the Etherealised Woman," by Cal McCrystal, in The Sunday Times, 9 October 1988 (Box 87, Folder 39)
    - "Entretien Avec Edna O'Brien," in Le Monde, 13 September 1969 (Box 87, Folder 40)
    - "Ernest & Edna, Living in Different Pasts," in London Evening Standard, 22 April 1988 (Box 87, Folder 41)
    - "Ernest and the Girl with the Green Eyes," by Anne Harris, in The Sunday Independent, 7 August 1994 (Box 87, Folder 42)
    - "El Escritor es como un Ladron o un Buen Cocinero Sin Testigos," by Ana Lilla Rojas Cano, in El Dia, 22 March 1998 (Box 87, Folder 43)
    - "Finding Company, the Hard Way," by Stuart Wavell, in The Guardian, 25 January 1980 (Box 87, Folder 44)
    - "For Edna O'Brien, Writing Is a Kind of Illness," by Susan Heller Anderson, in The New York Times, 11 October 1977 (Box 87, Folder 45)
    - "Frankfurt Spawns a Diaspora," by Denis; Staunton (Box 87, Folder 46)
    - "Getting Gothic with Edna O'Brien's 'Sister Imelda,'" by Wanda Balzano (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - "The Girl Who Wrote The Country Girls" (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - "A Great Tradition," by John Banville, in The Sunday Times, 1993 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - "Hard Working O'Brien," in London Evening Standard, 27 March 1972 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - "A Heavy Fall," by Boyd Tonkin, in New Statesman and Society, 28 August 1992 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - "How I Learned to Stop Loving the Wrong Men," by Corinna Honan, in Daily Mail, 7 September 1992 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - "How Running Revealed Man's Best 'High,'" by Ulick O'Connor, in The Sunday Times, 12 April 1981 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - "Hurricane Edna," by Liam MacGabhann, in This Week In Ireland, 17 October 1969 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - "'I Don't Have Time to be a Scarlet Woman,'" by Michael Sheridan (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - "I Need an Irish Angel She Purred," by John McEntee, in The Irish Press, 7 June 1988 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - "La Imaginacion y el Temor, ingredientes Para Ser Escritor," in La Cronica, 22 March 1998 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - "In Defence of Edna, A Great Talent," by Peter Eyre, 21 October 1992 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - "In for a Deep End," by Marie Dawson," in The Guardian, 2 October 1988 (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - "In Heaven with Edna," by Patricia Morison (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - "In the Combat Zone of Love," by Alan Levy, in International Herald Tribune, 4 May 1984 (Box 88, Folder 15)
    - "The Infamous Edna," by Tim Heald, in The Daily Telegraph, 15 October 1986 (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - "Interview: Edna O'Brien," by Mark Featherstone-Witty, in Palatinate, October 1971 (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - "Ireland in Her Agony is a Cultural 'Wasteland,'" 9 March 1973 (Box 88, Folder 18)
    - "Ireland's Wayward Writer, Still Raising Eyebrows," by Leslie Garis, in The New York Times, 23 December 1999 (Box 88, Folder 19)
    - "The Irrepressible Edna O'Brien," by Sabina Lawlor Clarke, July 1997 (Box 88, Folder 20)
    - "Kindred Spirits," in Telegraph Weekend Magazine, 24 March 1990 (Box 88, Folder 21)
    - "Labours of Love and Loss," by Shusha Guppy, in The Observer, 3 June 1990 (Box 88, Folder 22)
    - "The Last Word," in The Weekend Guardian, 29 August 1992 (Box 88, Folder 23)
    - "Life, Love and Edna," by Valerie Grove, in The Times, 22 April 1994 (Box 88, Folder 24)
    - "Life of O'Brien, by Eilenn Battersby, in The Irish Times, 14 October 1999 (Box 88, Folder 25)
    - "The Life of O'Brien," by Shusha Guppy, in London Portrait, November 1990 (Box 88, Folder 26)
    - "Lobster, AristoPats, and a Worthy Cause," in The Sunday Times, 24 June 1990 (Box 88, Folder 27)
    - "A Lot of Leaves to be Desired," by Daniel Johnson, in The Times, 11 July 1992 (Box 88, Folder 28)
    - "Love's Labours Lost," by Anthony Burgess, in The Daily Telegraph, 9 November 1988 (Box 88, Folder 29)
    - "Me Jewel and Darlin' Dublin," by Tom Davies, in The Observer, 8 July 1979 (Box 88, Folder 30)
    - "My Word Edna, How You Can Talk," by Jeannette Kupfermann (Box 88, Folder 31)
    - "Myth, Magic and the Gift of the Gab," by Philippa; Kennedy, in You, 12 May 1991 (Box 88, Folder 32)
    - "New Ratings War Should Not be Allowed to Spread," in Television Today, 25 August 1983 (Box 88, Folder 33)
    - "The Next O'Brien," in London Evening Standard, 24 April 1970 (Box 88, Folder 34)
    - "O'Brien and the Blessings of Obsession," by Louise Carbines, in The Age, 14 October 1994 (Box 88, Folder 35)
    - "O'Brien Country," by Christopher Hitchens, in Vanity Fair, March 1997 (Box 88, Folder 36)
    - "O'Brien Tells of Irish Isolation," by Debra Jopson (Box 88, Folder 37)
    - "Old Friends Gather to Fete Late Late," by Vincent Browns, in The Sunday Tribune, 20 September 1992 (Box 88, Folder 38)
    - "Our Edna-A Song of S.W.3.," by Elgy Gillespie, in The Irish Times, 10 June 1972 (Box 88, Folder 39)
    - "Out to Lunch," in Sunday Express Magazine, 6 September 1992 (Box 88, Folder 40)
    - "Owen Inspires Novel Friendship," 11 September 1991 (Box 88, Folder 41)
    - "Owen the Minister for Edna's Love" (Box 88, Folder 42)
    - "Pick of the Year," in The Sunday Times, 24 November 1996 (Box 88, Folder 43)
    - "Picks & Pans," in People, 11 October 1986 (Box 88, Folder 44)
    - "The Pleasure and the Pain," by Miriam Gross, in The Observer, 14 April 1985 (Box 88, Folder 45)
    - "Publishers Pow-wow Launches Millennium Editions," in The Irish Times, 8 June 1988 (Box 88, Folder 46)
    - "Pyrotechnics, Feuds, and Factions," by Sandra Dawson, in Australian Book Review, April 1970 (Box 88, Folder 47)
    - "Rambles in Ireland with Edna O'Brien," by Eileen Reilly (Box 88, Folder 48)
    - "Ranches of Isolation," by Tom Wihelmus, in The Hudson Review (Box 88, Folder 49)
    - "Reading Her Own Work," by P.K. Downey, 29 May 1972 (Box 88, Folder 50)
    - "Rebel Edna Finally Finds a Failte," by Justine McCarthy, in Irish Independent, 3 February 1993 (Box 88, Folder 51)
    - "Rich Stories Yet to be Told," in The Tribune Magazine, 5 November 1995 (Box 88, Folder 52)
    - "A Scandalous Woman," by Joe Jackson, in Hot Press, October 1992 (Box 88, Folder 53)
    - "A Schooling for Scandal," by Peter Guttridge in The Weekend Review, 12 June 1999 (Box 88, Folder 54)
    - "70 Movies for the Decades," by Michael Gray, in IE, November 1998 (Box 88, Folder 55)
    - "Sins and Lovers," by Terry Coleman, in The Guardian, 31 March 1994 (Box 88, Folder 56)
    - "A Soulful Journey Around Edna," by Madeleine Keane, in Sunday Independent, 7 February 1993 (Box 88, Folder 57)
    - "Sting a Fan of Edna O'Brien," by Helen Quinn (Box 88, Folder 58)
    - "Suitcase Studies," by Keith Waterhouse, in London Evening Standard, 15 August 1991 (Box 88, Folder 59)
    - "The Sweet One Gets Angry," by Mick Brown, in The Daily Telegraph, 17 April 1995 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - "Sweet Prose from Bitter Experience," by Megan Tresidder, in The Sunday Telegraph, 13 September 1992 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - "Talking with Edna O'Brien," in Cara, October-December 1970 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - "That Wife Mischief," by Terry Keane, in Sunday Independent, 12 June 1988 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - "Todos Somos Rehenes del Lugar Donde Provenimos: Edna O'Brien," by Jorge Luis Espinosa, in Uno Mas Uno, 21 March 1998 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - "The Trouble with Edna," by Stan Gebler Davies, in London Evening Standard, 19 October 1992 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - "Truly, Madly, Deeply," by Lucy Hughes-Hallett, in Vogue, October 1992 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - "The Unimportance of Being Ernest," in The Phoenix, 10 May 1985 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - "Upstaging the Poet," by Des Hickey, in Sunday Independent, 8 December 1991 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - "The Virtuous Rebel," by Ciaran McKeown, in Belfast Newsletter, 13 October 1992 (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - "West Edna," by John Hall, in The Guardian, 28 October 1972 (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - "Will Ban on Edna O'Brien's Books be Lifted?" (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - "A Writer's Retreat," by Fionnuala McHugh, in Country Homes, November 1992 (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Untitled article by Stan Gebler Davies, in Sunday Independent, 18 October 1992 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Untitled Interview (Box 89, Folder 15)
    - Promotional Material
    - Theatre programs (Box 89, Folder 16)
    - Promotional material (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Promotional material (Box 89, Folder 18)
    - Promotional material (Box 89, Folder 19)
    - August is a Wicked Month poster (Box OP4)
    - August is a Wicked Month promotional material (Box OP5)
    - Down by the River poster (Box OP6)
    - Down by the River poster (Box OP7)
    - Girls in Their Married Bliss poster (Box OP8)
    - House of Splendid Isolation poster (Box OP9)
    - The Irish Times Literature Prizes Shortlist 1999 poster (2) (Box OP10)
    - Night poster (2) (Box OP11)
    - O'Brien collage (Box OP12)
    - Time and Tide poster (Box OP13)
    - Time and Tide poster (3) (Box OP14)
    - Time and Tide promotional material (3) (Box OP15)
    - Virginia poster (Box OP16)
  - Other printed material, Subseries 6.3; Boxes 90-91
    - Individual Printed Works
    - Abrahamson, Emily, "Leaving Kalypso" (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Ardrey, Robert, "Four-Dimensional Man" (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Barry, Owen, Plum Krumble (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Dooley, Anne, "Hugh McDiarmid and the Gaelic Muse" (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Eckley, Grace, A Paradigm for the Fall of Humphrey Chimpden Earwicker (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Guntern-Gallati, Greta, Songlines (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "A Drink of Water" (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Heaney, Seamus and Felim Egan, "Towards a Collaboration" (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Madden, Gerard, Holy Island: Jewel of the Lough (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - McEneaney, Kevin, "Epithalamion" (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - O'Tuama, Sean, "The Lineage of Gaelic Love-Poetry from the Earliest Times" (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - Shaw, Caroline, "Massage for Health" (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Spier, Julius, The Hands of Children (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Steiner, George, "Leastness" (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Wesker, Arnold, "The House" (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Magazines and Pamphlets
    - The Bishop's Bonfire Programme (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - Bon Appetit, May 1996 (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Bronte Society Transactions, 1980 (Box 90, Folder 18)
    - The City Magazine, September 1946 (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - The Cotswold Rooster, 1966-1967 (Box 90, Folder 20)
    - The Drinking Man's Diet (Box 90, Folder 21)
    - Encore, January-February 1961 (Box 90, Folder 22)
    - The Froebel School: School Magazine, 1958, 1960, and 1966-1967 (Box 90, Folder 23)
    - The Funday Times, 25 February 1990 (Box 90, Folder 24)
    - Green Farm Magazine, Summer 1985 (Box 90, Folder 25)
    - Green Tongues (Box 90, Folder 26)
    - Grian, Spring 1995 (Box 90, Folder 27)
    - Investors Chronicle, 27 January-2 February 1989 (Box 90, Folder 28)
    - The Irish Messenger of the Sacred Heart, December 1964 (Box 90, Folder 29)
    - Kensington Drama Club pamphlet (Box 90, Folder 30)
    - Laurence Corner pamphlet (Box 90, Folder 31)
    - Long Day's Journey into Night programme (Box 90, Folder 32)
    - The Mermaid Theatre: A Sean O'Casey Festival pamphlet (Box 90, Folder 33)
    - Modern Poetry in Translation, 1969-1972 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Modern Poetry in Translation, 1977-1979 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Network, Summer 1995 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Number Three Saint James's Street, Autumn 1958 and Spring 1977 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Opening of the National Theatre programme, 25 October 1976 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Peckham Poets (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Samuel Beckett: As the Story was Told (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Shig's Review (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Spring Awakening programme (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Suddenly Last Summer programme (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - The Sunday Times Magazine, 7 April 1985 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Teac Synge (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Words from a Robeless Way (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Writers News, February 1968 (Box 91, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 91, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 91, Folder 16)
    - Promotional material (Box 91, Folder 17)
- Audio-visual material, Series 7; Boxes 92-93, OP's 17-21
  The series contains audio-visual material such as audiotapes, videotapes, and photographs. The audio and videotapes include readings by and interviews with O'Brien and are arranged chronologically. Present also are photographs of O'Brien, her family, and others, including Sir Ian McKellen, Jackie Onassis, Ted Turner, and Jane Fonda.
  Organized into three subseries: (7.1) Audiotapes, (7.2) Videotapes, and (7.3) Photographs.
  - Audiotapes, Subseries 7.1; Box 92
    - Readings by O'Brien
    - "Brother," from Lantern Slides, and excerpts from Time and Tide [digitized; filename 4619-4620] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Answering machine messages and House of Splendid Isolation, July 1993 [digitized; filename 4621-4622] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Interviews with O'Brien
    - "A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Girl," 2 September 1985 [digitized; filename 4555] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "O'Brien and Trevor," 22 May 1990 [digitized; filename 4556-4557] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Writers' Bookshelves: Edna O'Brien," 31 October 1990 [digitized; filename 4558] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Public Radio Book Show," 30 December 1990 [digitized; filename 4559] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Other audiotapes
    - "Johnny En Jones" [digitized; filename 4618] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Philip Larkin's "Deception," read by Harold Pinter [digitized; filename 4623-4624] (Box -, Folder -)
  - Videotapes, Subseries 7.2; Box 92
    - Interviews with O'Brien
    - The Today Show, 12 December 1988 (Box DVD1, Folder -)
    - The Book Show, 16 April, 1994 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - The Book Show, 6 October, 1996 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - "The Vincenet Browne Interview", 1997 (Box DVD2, Folder -)
    - "Writers on Writing: Edna O'Brien," 1998 (Box DVD3, Folder -)
    - Other videotapes
    - Bookmark: Samuel Beckett-As the Story was Told, Part 1 (Box DVD4, Folder -)
    - Bookmark: Samuel Beckett-As the Story was Told, Part 2 (Box DVD5, Folder -)
    - "For Seamus Heaney," A Tribute on the Occasion of the Nobel Prize for Literature Award 1995 (Box DVD6, Folder -)
    - The Road to the Bright City, 13 April 1993 (Box DVD7, Folder -)
    - The Queen's University of Belfast, Graduation 1999 (Box DVD8, Folder -)
  - Photographs, Subseries 7.3; Box 93; OP17-21
    - Edna O'Brien (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Edna O'Brien (Box OP17)
    - Edna O'Brien (Box OP18)
    - Edna O'Brien with family (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Edna O'Brien with others (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Family (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Carlos Gebler (Box OP19)
    - Sasha Gebler (Box OP20)
    - Others (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Sir Ian McKellen (Box OP21)
    - Places (Box 93, Folder 6)
- Ephemera, 1944-1999, Series 8; Box 94; OP 22
  The series contains personal items belonging to Edna O'Brien. Personal materials found in the collection date from ca. 1944 through 1999. Personal items include possessions from the author’s convent school education, including a copy of O'Brien’s sodality manual, inscribed 9 February, 1948. The manual contains a number of prayers, many of which are signed and dated ca. 1948. The collection also contains prayer books and mass cards. Additional items in the series include small gift items from family and friends.
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters Honorary Membership (Box OP22)
  - Autograph Book, 1944 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Book of Common Prayer (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Brooch (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Handbag (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Madame Bovary programme with notes from cast (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Manual of Prayer (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Sodality Manual (Box 94, Folder 7)
- Collected material, 1971-1979, Series 9; Box 95
  The series contains materials acquired from various sources. It is composed of letters written by O'Brian. For details regarding the provenance of specific items in this artificially assembled portion of the collection, consult the library staff.
  - Correspondence to Joanne Trautmann Banks, 1971-1979 (Box 95, Folder 1)